<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Space Station 14: Multiplayer Disaster Simulator on Space Station 14</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/</link><description>Recent content in Space Station 14: Multiplayer Disaster Simulator on Space Station 14</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spacestation14.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Launcher Update v0.33.0</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-08-01-launcher-update-v0-32-0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-08-01-launcher-update-v0-32-0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Updater improvements and localization updates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 108 - (Harmpack, Jump Boots, Artifact Glue)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-07-22-liltenhead-108/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-07-22-liltenhead-108/</guid><description>Two new science technologies can be researched on the station, the first of which are jump boots. These allow the user to traverse potentially lethal surfaces with ease, no power required. The second is the harmpack; this backpack allows the users to enjoy two extra functional arms, for whatever purposes you may have! Artifact glue can allow for endless riches or destruction to whatever artifact the glue is applied to. The spray painter now allows for tile perfect decals, alongside other various options.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 107 - (S̶l̶u̶g̶c̶a̶t Scurrets, Stamina Damage Resistance, Salvage Tweaks)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-07-09-liltenhead-107/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-07-09-liltenhead-107/</guid><description>Scurrets make their first appearance on the station. They are a ghost role that is purchasable for 25k spesos. Currently they are only for emotional support. A new Atmos device was added that allows technicians even greater control over the pressure in their networks. Most syndicate hardsuits now feature some level of stamina resistance, giving them greater power over stun weaponry. There have been sweeping tweaks across salvage, generally nerfing all of their weaponry while simultaneously debuffing their foes.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 106 - (Exo Station, Estoc DMR, Barotrauma Damage Buff)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-06-23-liltenhead-106/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-06-23-liltenhead-106/</guid><description>A new station joins the game; it is named Exo. This station features alien architecture, different department layouts, and other stylized choices. A new syndicate weapon named the Estoc is a longer-range option, with not quite as much stopping power as the C20 or Bulldog. Thieving gloves were removed, meaning now only the thief antag can steal from people quickly and stealthily. Scrap armor allows for tiders to make discount blood-reds, and now mad scientists can turn you into a smart corgi!</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 105 - (Pipe Stacking, Text Highlighting, Sentry Turret Controls)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-06-10-liltenhead-105/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-06-10-liltenhead-105/</guid><description>Atmos techs can now layer multiple pipes on the same tile and even combine them into one singular output. This offers the previous complex systems of pipe stacking while still looking great. You can now highlight any words you want, from your name to your current job. This will allow you to stay more focused on things pertaining to you, especially helpful in busy radio situations. Sentry turrets, like the ones found in AI cores, will now have consoles to configure their settings further.</description></item><item><title>Launcher Update v0.32.0</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-06-04-launcher-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-06-04-launcher-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>Minor fixes and localization updates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 95 - (Plasma Station, Elkridge Station, QoL Improvements)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-01-20-liltenhead-95/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-01-20-liltenhead-95/</guid><description>Two new maps were added to the game. Plasma, a medium population station, is a unique map that features plasma pools, a lot of asteroid rocks, and unusual hallway designs not found in other stations. In theme with the map, the TEG is the primary power method of the station. The second map is known as Elkridge. This is a low population map with a cozy design and a few unique takes on areas like the bridge.</description></item><item><title>10 Years of Space Station 14</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/25-01-19-10-years-of-space-station-14/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/25-01-19-10-years-of-space-station-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>10 years ago, the standalone SS13 remake project was open sourced, and Space Station 14 was born.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 94 - (Chameleon PDA, Extra Syndi Discounts, New Ion Storm Prompts)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-01-06-liltenhead-94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-01-06-liltenhead-94/</guid><description>The chameleon PDA is the newest piece of equipment in the Syndicate&amp;rsquo;s roster. You can now almost go completely undercover as any member of any department (with exceptions to mindshielded ones). Syndicate agents will now also enjoy more discounted options to potentially choose from in their uplinks. There have been tweaks to various construction objects, like reinforced tables requiring a welder, and wooden walls no longer requiring steel. Moffs will now enjoy new cotton food options, and borgs may or may not enjoy their new ion law possibilities.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 93 - (Loop Station, Gate Station, Holopads)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-12-30-liltenhead-93/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-12-30-liltenhead-93/</guid><description>Two new stations have been introduced to the game; they are named &amp;ldquo;Loop&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Gate.&amp;rdquo;. Loop is a medium population map focused around a centralized security and medical department, with wide open hallways and an easy-to-navigate layout. Gate is a very complex map focused around gateways and shuttles as the primary method to get between departments. Each department is segmented far away from each other in space, with thin arms connecting them all together.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 80 - (Executions, Custom Burgers, Thief Beacon)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-08-11-liltenhead-80/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-08-11-liltenhead-80/</guid><description>Melee executions allow for sharp-bladed weapons to ignore armor and inflict massive damage. Melee executions may be performed on yourself or targets that are incapacitated/cuffed. Custom burgers have been added, allowing for actual custom recipes that don&amp;rsquo;t require something like a microwave. The thief beacon allows for thieves to steal items and not have to hoard them on their character all shift. This also allows for stealing animals and structures way more conveniently.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 79 - (New Reagents, Cutter Machine, PNG Export)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-08-04-liltenhead-79/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-08-04-liltenhead-79/</guid><description>This week brings some new reagents and reworked chloral hydrate. These new reagents include potassium iodide, which helps prevent radiation damage, and haloperidol, which removes stimulants and hallucinogens from your system. Drowsiness is also a new symptom and side effect where you may fall asleep at random; chloral hydrate also now makes you drowsy instead of knocking you out once you reach the unit threshold. The cutter machine allows for making more specific and decorated floor tiles.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 78 - (Reinforcement Buffs, New Botany Mutations, Dragon Body Fixes)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-28-liltenhead-78/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-28-liltenhead-78/</guid><description>This week brings major buffs to both syndicate and nuclear operative reinforcements. Nuclear operative reinforcements now are loaded up with a blood-red and a chest rig, just like a regular nukie. Syndicate reinforcements now have loadouts ranging from medical items to spy equipment. Atmos techs can now build pipes inside walls, giving them extra room for whatever projects they are working on. Dead space dragons will no longer despawn, meaning that anyone who got devoured won&amp;rsquo;t disappear into the void.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 77 - (Syndicate Raid Suit, Throwing Rework, Bartending Tweaks)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-77/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-77/</guid><description>This week brings a powerful new suit of armor, available only to nuclear operatives. It is a well-rounded suit that is not space-faring, meaning it must be used with specific plans in mind. Throwing has been changed to allow for significantly more precision when throwing objects and weapons. Bartenders now have to shake or stir specific drinks, giving a bit more variety in their bartending methods.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 76 - (Vox, Giant Asteroid Dungeons, Nukie Nerfs)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-76/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-76/</guid><description>This week introduces a bird-like species known as the Vox. The Vox must breathe pure nitrogen; otherwise, they will take hefty poison damage until they get pure nitrogen in their lungs. Salvage has received some new content in the form of &amp;ldquo;VGRoid.&amp;rdquo; The VGRoid is a giant asteroid with hundreds of ore deposits and salvage expedition dungeons that generate on them. The aesteroids are filled with danger, but have more materials than you&amp;rsquo;d ever need to get through a shift.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 74 - (Meteor Swarm Revamp, Pipe Stacking Removal, General Game Balancing)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-06-16-liltenhead-74/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-06-16-liltenhead-74/</guid><description>The content freeze is over, and there were a number of notable PRs merged during the freeze and shortly after. Meteor swarms are now much more deadly and can breach through many layers of walls. Pipe stacking was removed, changing the way Atmos has to do pretty much everything. Many combat QoL additions were added, such as wielding autodropping items, shooting over stunned people, etc. Finally, there were a ton of QoL features and balance changes across various levels of content in the game.</description></item><item><title>Launcher now open for translation!</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/24-06-03-launcher-translation-now-open/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/24-06-03-launcher-translation-now-open/</guid><description>&lt;p>The launcher is now open for translation by YOU! Know a language that isn&amp;rsquo;t English? You can help!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 73 - (Ghost Role Raffles, Bullets Pass Over Crit Bodies, Robotics Console)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-12-liltenhead-73/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-12-liltenhead-73/</guid><description>This week brings loads of new features and content additions. Impactful ghost roles like ninjas or dragons now have a raffle before the role is given out. This gives all players interested in the role an equally random chance of obtaining the role once the timer ends. Space dragons can breathe fire now, ninjas have a new objective, and emagged cyborgs are more stealthy. Also this week, bullets will now pass over critically injured mobs unless you aim directly at them.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 72 - (Train Station, Sleeper Agents, Anti Rotting Chem)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-05-liltenhead-72/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-05-liltenhead-72/</guid><description>This week brings a new station to play on; it is named Train Station. The train station features departments stacked in a linear fashion that resembles a train shape. The syndicate not only sends agents at the beginning of a shift but may also awaken sleeper agents in the middle of the shift. Chemists can now make an anti-rot reagent with a little help from botany to prevent crew members from perma dying.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 71 - (New Map, Slime Species Update, Portable Recharger)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-28-liltenhead-71/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-28-liltenhead-71/</guid><description>This week brings a new station to play on; it is named Oasis. This station features a large park at its center and a massive mining-themed perma brig that is not attached to the station, which leaves a lot of room for unique gameplay. Syndicate librarians may now purchase cane swords; syndicates in general may now purchase syndicats. Science has received some tech tree changes, with the cargo telepad being bumped down to tier two, as well as new tier three tech under the arsenal tree provides a portable recharger for all your mobile battery needs.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 70 - (Loadouts, Jukebox, Killer Tomato)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-21-liltenhead-70/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-21-liltenhead-70/</guid><description>This week brings customizable role-specific loadouts. In the lobby, you can customize your loadout for every role, from jumpsuits to backpack types. Botanists can now grow their own personalized army through the form of killer tomatoes. The chameleon projector allows syndicate agents to blend into their environment by copying the appearance of nearly any object. As well as other content additions, bug fixes, and balancing tweaks over the week.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 69 - (Botany QoL, Cryo Sleep Manifests)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-14-liltenhead-69/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-14-liltenhead-69/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 68 - (RCD Overhaul, New Anomaly Mechanics, Inventory QoL)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-10-liltenhead-68/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-10-liltenhead-68/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Website Update</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/24-04-01-website-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/24-04-01-website-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t an April&amp;rsquo;s Fools joke, I just happened to do this on Aprils First.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 67 - (Cleaning Grenades, Explosion Changes, Rubber Bullet Removal)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-31-liltenhead-67/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-31-liltenhead-67/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 66 - (Throwing Knives, Lone Ops Buff, Hacking Tweaks)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-24-liltenhead-66/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-24-liltenhead-66/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 65 - Additions (IED Changes, Pipebomb, Plant Biomass Reclaimer)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-18-liltenhead-65/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-18-liltenhead-65/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Progress Report #39: Happy Holidelays</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/23-03-06-progress-report-39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/23-03-06-progress-report-39/</guid><description>&lt;p>Remember when progress reports used to be released on time every month? Neither do we! PR39 covers November and December 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #38: Oh Baby a Triple</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-11-30-progress-report-38/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-11-30-progress-report-38/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh yeah. We have a ton of huge changes like oldchat, machine upgrade improvements, playtime tracking, and more! We have some catching up to do, so this PR covers August through October 2022. As a consequence, we&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;del>gone insane&lt;/del> skipped the Minor Changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #37: Love, Geoff, and Robots</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-10-31-progress-report-37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-10-31-progress-report-37/</guid><description>&lt;p>Better late than never, we&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully get back on track soon. (And if you&amp;rsquo;d like to help contribute, progress report writers are always welcome!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #36: Too Much of a Good Thing</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-07-27-progress-report-36/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-07-27-progress-report-36/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s so much new content that at least one Progress Report author has been driven mad! We&amp;rsquo;ve even surpassed /tg/station 13 by contributions per month.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #35: Going Nuclear</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-06-25-progress-report-35/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-06-25-progress-report-35/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nuclear Operatives, magic, and more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #34: Manifest Destiny</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-05-25-progress-report-34/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-05-25-progress-report-34/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tons of improvements to the SS14 experience, and more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #33: Delta Variant</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-04-30-progress-report-33/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-04-30-progress-report-33/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s so many changes we couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to cover them all!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #32: Geoff</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-04-01-progress-report-32/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-04-01-progress-report-32/</guid><description>&lt;p>As promised in the last progress report, here&amp;rsquo;s the second half of our two-part special! This part covers February 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #31: Duck, Duck, Weh</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-03-16-progress-report-31/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-03-16-progress-report-31/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a minute since the last Progress Report, and there&amp;rsquo;s been so many changes that we had to break this one up into two parts! This part covers January 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #30: A Short Freeze for Winter</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-01-11-progress-report-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-01-11-progress-report-30/</guid><description>&lt;p>Even with the winter holidays and a week-long feature freeze, December capped off a busy year for Space Station 14. In 2021, Space Station 14 had 2184 contributions, easily beating the 2020 contribution count of 1498.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #29: A Lot To Unpack</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-12-09-progress-report-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-12-09-progress-report-29/</guid><description>&lt;p>Space Station 14 underwent so many changes in November that we had to split them off into a separate progress report. From November 4th to December 4th, the Space Station 14 code base had 357 contributions made - easily beating the two month period covered by Progress Report 28.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #28: Atmosia Rising</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-11-24-progress-report-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-11-24-progress-report-28/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last couple of months have been a huge step forward for Space Station 14, with a total of 315 contributions made to the SS14 codebase between September 29th and November 3rd, and nearly 700 commits to SS14 and the RobustToolbox engine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #27: Transported to the Chess Dimension</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-10-01-progress-report-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-10-01-progress-report-27/</guid><description>Website Upgrade As you may have noticed, our official website has gotten a major facelift thanks to PJB. We also commissioned some nice new background art from AsPev as a replacement for our old one which was a little crusty. You can download a full resolution of it here.
Updated Playtest Schedule We&amp;rsquo;re moving playtests to a consistent schedule due to their popularity and developers wanting more feedback from the community on the state of the game.</description></item><item><title>Progress Report #26: Lītigium In Forīs</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-05-07-progress-report-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-05-07-progress-report-26/</guid><description>Official Forums Space Station 14 now has an official forum! You can login to it with your SS14 account.
The forum will mainly be used for ban appeals and other administrative stuff so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty barebones for now. If it gets enough activity we&amp;rsquo;ll add more general forums and stuff.
Please read the rules before posting.
Content Physics Rework Contributed by metalgearsloth and Acruid.
A huge thanks to metalgearsloth for slaving over a complete physics rework for SS14.</description></item><item><title>Progress Report #25: Blowing Off Steam</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-02-12-progress-report-25/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-02-12-progress-report-25/</guid><description>Playtest We&amp;rsquo;re proud to announce that Space Station 14 is now available through the new Steam Playtest feature. Originally we were planning to do a full release through Early Access, but we felt that a more limited release was a better match for the current state of SS14 development.
To gain access, simply visit the SS14 store page and click Request Access. You&amp;rsquo;ll be added to the pool of people who are waiting, which we randomly draw from when we feel we could use more players.</description></item><item><title>Progress Report #24: Atmos Sim Remake Now Simulates Atmos</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-10-16-progress-report-24/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-10-16-progress-report-24/</guid><description>Barebones rounds! Throughout the years, we&amp;rsquo;ve put a lot of work into developing the engine and framework necessary for Space Station 14 to have playable content. Last year, we transitioned to developing player-facing features and gameplay in earnest, and we&amp;rsquo;ve made a lot of progress in that short timespan!
SS14 now has playable, albeit barebones, rounds. As we add more features the number of complex interactions grows, and so does the need for testing the game with real players.</description></item><item><title>Progress Report #23: We Didn't Want To Wait Until Atmos Was Done</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-07-22-progress-report-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-07-22-progress-report-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sadly atmos is not done yet. A lot of other stuff is though!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #22: Full Steam Ahead</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-06-07-progress-report-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-06-07-progress-report-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been 3 months since the last post, we have a lot to tell you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #21: Colonial Marines, lighting, features</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-02-24-progress-report-21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-02-24-progress-report-21/</guid><description>&lt;p>We have big news for everyone who enjoys slaying meat sacks as a xenomorph, futilely hiding in a locker as a survivor, or being eaten alive as a marine&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #20: 2020 Resolution Failed</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-01-24-progress-report-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/20-01-24-progress-report-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>Writing progress reports is hard. Usually it isn&amp;rsquo;t even writing the progress report itself, it&amp;rsquo;s making the content we&amp;rsquo;ve added presentable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #19: 2x The Wait, 4x The Content</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-10-22-progress-report-19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-10-22-progress-report-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kept you waiting, huh?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #18: Speech Bubbles &amp; Slightly Better Launcher</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-08-24-progress-report-18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-08-24-progress-report-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>Writing these into sections is hard, did you know that?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #17: Main UI Plans</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-07-24-progress-report-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-07-24-progress-report-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the biggest things that scare people away from SS13 is, of course, the terrible user interface.
So, let&amp;rsquo;s make sure that isn&amp;rsquo;t the case for SS14!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #16: Outline, Use, Kaboom</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-06-07-progress-report-16/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-06-07-progress-report-16/</guid><description>&lt;p>As it turns out, &lt;em>re-imagining&lt;/em> SS13 is a bit harder than simply &lt;em>re-making&lt;/em> it. Not that that deters us.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #15: Bye Godot</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-05-12-progress-report-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-05-12-progress-report-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Godot is finally dead, but it will always be there in our hearts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #14: Content &amp; More Server</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-04-22-progress-report-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-04-22-progress-report-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>This time on SS14: neat features and neat server features.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #13: Permanent Public Server.</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-04-02-progress-report-13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-04-02-progress-report-13/</guid><description>&lt;p>Working on a massive project like this can be quite daunting. &amp;ldquo;Remake SS13&amp;rdquo; is quite a clear goal but far from concrete. Having intermediate goals to work towards is important. So for now, my goal at least is to get a permanent public server running.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #12: Suddenly, Progress!</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-03-23-progress-report-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-03-23-progress-report-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>Didn&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;d already see a new progress report now, did you?
And especially not such a packed one!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #11: UI &amp; Animations</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-03-17-progress-report-11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-03-17-progress-report-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>The GUI system is much more complete now, so most interfaces work now.
I also decided to actually code something NEW instead of purely catching up to Godot.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #10: Nothing To Say For Ourselves</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-02-20-progress-report-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/19-02-20-progress-report-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yeah I honestly have nothing to say for myself. You have the right to laugh.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #9: The One Where We Implemented New Features</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-12-14-progress-report-9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-12-14-progress-report-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yeah, we really don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to say here, outside of &amp;ldquo;look at all these features!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #8: Writing Some Content</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-09-19-progress-report-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-09-19-progress-report-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s pretty nice to get to a point where we can worry purely about content without having to juggle the engine around all the time. I think we&amp;rsquo;re getting close to the point of reaching that now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #7: Visual</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-06-24-progress-report-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-06-24-progress-report-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fancy graphics and less fancy menus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #6: Never say 'few'</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-04-13-progress-report-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-04-13-progress-report-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>The wait is over.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #5: Waiting for Godot</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-02-26-progress-report-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/18-02-26-progress-report-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>So when was the last progress report made? November right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh jeez.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nightly Builds Up (Properly!)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-10-25-nightly-builds-up-properly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-10-25-nightly-builds-up-properly/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ss14.silvertorch5.io/jenkins/job/SS14%20Content%20Build/">Get your Windows, MacOS and Linux builds here!&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nightly Builds Up!</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-10-21-nightly-builds-up-sorta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-10-21-nightly-builds-up-sorta/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ss14.silvertorch5.io/jenkins/job/SS14%20Content%20Build/">Nightly Windows &amp;amp; Linux builds here!&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #4: Robust Content Framework</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-08-17-progress-report-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-08-17-progress-report-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple weeks since the last progress report, and lots has happened since then. Refactors, setting up the content repo, and more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #3: Ending the pre-alpha</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-07-25-progress-report-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-07-25-progress-report-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>So stuff&amp;rsquo;s been quiet for the past 14 days. I can give you an annoying excuse or I can just accept that weekly progress reports aren&amp;rsquo;t working &lt;em>yet&lt;/em>. As such &lt;strong>progress reports will no longer be scheduled and done whenever we feel there&amp;rsquo;s something big to report&lt;/strong>, like today!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress report #2: Refactor Hell</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-07-10-progress-report-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-07-10-progress-report-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The progress report took a bit to get here, because I uploaded #1 two days too late, and not a lot of substance for a report happened between then and when #2 should&amp;rsquo;ve happened. Not the case anymore though, got plenty to write about this time!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #1: Revive</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-06-26-progress-report-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/17-06-26-progress-report-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re reading this on the new website for SS14! After &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/Q3cUg29.gif">lots of hard work with CSS&lt;/a>, the website is ready to recieve progress reports and other news.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>