<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Space Station 14</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/categories/update/</link><description>Recent content on Space Station 14</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spacestation14.com/categories/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Update Vlog - 76 - (Vox, Giant Asteroid Dungeons, Nukie Nerfs)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-76/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-76/</guid><description>This week introduces a bird-like species known as the Vox. The Vox must breathe pure nitrogen; otherwise, they will take hefty poison damage until they get pure nitrogen in their lungs. Salvage has received some new content in the form of &amp;ldquo;VGRoid.&amp;rdquo; The VGRoid is a giant asteroid with hundreds of ore deposits and salvage expedition dungeons that generate on them. The aesteroids are filled with danger, but have more materials than you&amp;rsquo;d ever need to get through a shift.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 74 - (Meteor Swarm Revamp, Pipe Stacking Removal, General Game Balancing)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-06-16-liltenhead-74/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-06-16-liltenhead-74/</guid><description>The content freeze is over, and there were a number of notable PRs merged during the freeze and shortly after. Meteor swarms are now much more deadly and can breach through many layers of walls. Pipe stacking was removed, changing the way Atmos has to do pretty much everything. Many combat QoL additions were added, such as wielding autodropping items, shooting over stunned people, etc. Finally, there were a ton of QoL features and balance changes across various levels of content in the game.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 73 - (Ghost Role Raffles, Bullets Pass Over Crit Bodies, Robotics Console)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-12-liltenhead-73/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-12-liltenhead-73/</guid><description>This week brings loads of new features and content additions. Impactful ghost roles like ninjas or dragons now have a raffle before the role is given out. This gives all players interested in the role an equally random chance of obtaining the role once the timer ends. Space dragons can breathe fire now, ninjas have a new objective, and emagged cyborgs are more stealthy. Also this week, bullets will now pass over critically injured mobs unless you aim directly at them.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 72 - (Train Station, Sleeper Agents, Anti Rotting Chem)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-05-liltenhead-72/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-05-liltenhead-72/</guid><description>This week brings a new station to play on; it is named Train Station. The train station features departments stacked in a linear fashion that resembles a train shape. The syndicate not only sends agents at the beginning of a shift but may also awaken sleeper agents in the middle of the shift. Chemists can now make an anti-rot reagent with a little help from botany to prevent crew members from perma dying.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 71 - (New Map, Slime Species Update, Portable Recharger)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-28-liltenhead-71/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-28-liltenhead-71/</guid><description>This week brings a new station to play on; it is named Oasis. This station features a large park at its center and a massive mining-themed perma brig that is not attached to the station, which leaves a lot of room for unique gameplay. Syndicate librarians may now purchase cane swords; syndicates in general may now purchase syndicats. Science has received some tech tree changes, with the cargo telepad being bumped down to tier two, as well as new tier three tech under the arsenal tree provides a portable recharger for all your mobile battery needs.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 70 - (Loadouts, Jukebox, Killer Tomato)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-21-liltenhead-70/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-21-liltenhead-70/</guid><description>This week brings customizable role-specific loadouts. In the lobby, you can customize your loadout for every role, from jumpsuits to backpack types. Botanists can now grow their own personalized army through the form of killer tomatoes. The chameleon projector allows syndicate agents to blend into their environment by copying the appearance of nearly any object. As well as other content additions, bug fixes, and balancing tweaks over the week.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 69 - (Botany QoL, Cryo Sleep Manifests)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-14-liltenhead-69/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-14-liltenhead-69/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 68 - (RCD Overhaul, New Anomaly Mechanics, Inventory QoL)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-10-liltenhead-68/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-10-liltenhead-68/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 67 - (Cleaning Grenades, Explosion Changes, Rubber Bullet Removal)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-31-liltenhead-67/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-31-liltenhead-67/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 66 - (Throwing Knives, Lone Ops Buff, Hacking Tweaks)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-24-liltenhead-66/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-24-liltenhead-66/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 65 - Additions (IED Changes, Pipebomb, Plant Biomass Reclaimer)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-18-liltenhead-65/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-18-liltenhead-65/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Progress Report #39: Happy Holidelays</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/23-03-06-progress-report-39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/23-03-06-progress-report-39/</guid><description>&lt;p>Remember when progress reports used to be released on time every month? Neither do we! PR39 covers November and December 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #38: Oh Baby a Triple</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-11-30-progress-report-38/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-11-30-progress-report-38/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh yeah. We have a ton of huge changes like oldchat, machine upgrade improvements, playtime tracking, and more! We have some catching up to do, so this PR covers August through October 2022. As a consequence, we&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;del>gone insane&lt;/del> skipped the Minor Changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #37: Love, Geoff, and Robots</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-10-31-progress-report-37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-10-31-progress-report-37/</guid><description>&lt;p>Better late than never, we&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully get back on track soon. (And if you&amp;rsquo;d like to help contribute, progress report writers are always welcome!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #36: Too Much of a Good Thing</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-07-27-progress-report-36/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-07-27-progress-report-36/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s so much new content that at least one Progress Report author has been driven mad! We&amp;rsquo;ve even surpassed /tg/station 13 by contributions per month.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #35: Going Nuclear</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-06-25-progress-report-35/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-06-25-progress-report-35/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nuclear Operatives, magic, and more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #34: Manifest Destiny</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-05-25-progress-report-34/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-05-25-progress-report-34/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tons of improvements to the SS14 experience, and more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #33: Delta Variant</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-04-30-progress-report-33/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-04-30-progress-report-33/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s so many changes we couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to cover them all!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #32: Geoff</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-04-01-progress-report-32/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-04-01-progress-report-32/</guid><description>&lt;p>As promised in the last progress report, here&amp;rsquo;s the second half of our two-part special! This part covers February 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #31: Duck, Duck, Weh</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-03-16-progress-report-31/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-03-16-progress-report-31/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a minute since the last Progress Report, and there&amp;rsquo;s been so many changes that we had to break this one up into two parts! This part covers January 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #30: A Short Freeze for Winter</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-01-11-progress-report-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/22-01-11-progress-report-30/</guid><description>&lt;p>Even with the winter holidays and a week-long feature freeze, December capped off a busy year for Space Station 14. In 2021, Space Station 14 had 2184 contributions, easily beating the 2020 contribution count of 1498.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #29: A Lot To Unpack</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-12-09-progress-report-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-12-09-progress-report-29/</guid><description>&lt;p>Space Station 14 underwent so many changes in November that we had to split them off into a separate progress report. From November 4th to December 4th, the Space Station 14 code base had 357 contributions made - easily beating the two month period covered by Progress Report 28.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #28: Atmosia Rising</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-11-24-progress-report-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-11-24-progress-report-28/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last couple of months have been a huge step forward for Space Station 14, with a total of 315 contributions made to the SS14 codebase between September 29th and November 3rd, and nearly 700 commits to SS14 and the RobustToolbox engine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress Report #27: Transported to the Chess Dimension</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-10-01-progress-report-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/post/21-10-01-progress-report-27/</guid><description>Website Upgrade As you may have noticed, our official website has gotten a major facelift thanks to PJB. We also commissioned some nice new background art from AsPev as a replacement for our old one which was a little crusty. You can download a full resolution of it here.
Updated Playtest Schedule We&amp;rsquo;re moving playtests to a consistent schedule due to their popularity and developers wanting more feedback from the community on the state of the game.</description></item></channel></rss>