<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Updates on Space Station 14</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/</link><description>Recent content in Updates on Space Station 14</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spacestation14.com/updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Update Vlog - 94 - (Chameleon PDA, Extra Syndi Discounts, New Ion Storm Prompts)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-01-06-liltenhead-94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-01-06-liltenhead-94/</guid><description>The chameleon PDA is the newest piece of equipment in the Syndicate&amp;rsquo;s roster. You can now almost go completely undercover as any member of any department (with exceptions to mindshielded ones). Syndicate agents will now also enjoy more discounted options to potentially choose from in their uplinks. There have been tweaks to various construction objects, like reinforced tables requiring a welder, and wooden walls no longer requiring steel. Moffs will now enjoy new cotton food options, and borgs may or may not enjoy their new ion law possibilities.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 93 - (Loop Station, Gate Station, Holopads)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-12-30-liltenhead-93/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/25-12-30-liltenhead-93/</guid><description>Two new stations have been introduced to the game; they are named &amp;ldquo;Loop&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Gate.&amp;rdquo;. Loop is a medium population map focused around a centralized security and medical department, with wide open hallways and an easy-to-navigate layout. Gate is a very complex map focused around gateways and shuttles as the primary method to get between departments. Each department is segmented far away from each other in space, with thin arms connecting them all together.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 80 - (Executions, Custom Burgers, Thief Beacon)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-08-11-liltenhead-80/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-08-11-liltenhead-80/</guid><description>Melee executions allow for sharp-bladed weapons to ignore armor and inflict massive damage. Melee executions may be performed on yourself or targets that are incapacitated/cuffed. Custom burgers have been added, allowing for actual custom recipes that don&amp;rsquo;t require something like a microwave. The thief beacon allows for thieves to steal items and not have to hoard them on their character all shift. This also allows for stealing animals and structures way more conveniently.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 79 - (New Reagents, Cutter Machine, PNG Export)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-08-04-liltenhead-79/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-08-04-liltenhead-79/</guid><description>This week brings some new reagents and reworked chloral hydrate. These new reagents include potassium iodide, which helps prevent radiation damage, and haloperidol, which removes stimulants and hallucinogens from your system. Drowsiness is also a new symptom and side effect where you may fall asleep at random; chloral hydrate also now makes you drowsy instead of knocking you out once you reach the unit threshold. The cutter machine allows for making more specific and decorated floor tiles.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 78 - (Reinforcement Buffs, New Botany Mutations, Dragon Body Fixes)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-28-liltenhead-78/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-28-liltenhead-78/</guid><description>This week brings major buffs to both syndicate and nuclear operative reinforcements. Nuclear operative reinforcements now are loaded up with a blood-red and a chest rig, just like a regular nukie. Syndicate reinforcements now have loadouts ranging from medical items to spy equipment. Atmos techs can now build pipes inside walls, giving them extra room for whatever projects they are working on. Dead space dragons will no longer despawn, meaning that anyone who got devoured won&amp;rsquo;t disappear into the void.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 77 - (Syndicate Raid Suit, Throwing Rework, Bartending Tweaks)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-77/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-77/</guid><description>This week brings a powerful new suit of armor, available only to nuclear operatives. It is a well-rounded suit that is not space-faring, meaning it must be used with specific plans in mind. Throwing has been changed to allow for significantly more precision when throwing objects and weapons. Bartenders now have to shake or stir specific drinks, giving a bit more variety in their bartending methods.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 76 - (Vox, Giant Asteroid Dungeons, Nukie Nerfs)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-76/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-07-07-liltenhead-76/</guid><description>This week introduces a bird-like species known as the Vox. The Vox must breathe pure nitrogen; otherwise, they will take hefty poison damage until they get pure nitrogen in their lungs. Salvage has received some new content in the form of &amp;ldquo;VGRoid.&amp;rdquo; The VGRoid is a giant asteroid with hundreds of ore deposits and salvage expedition dungeons that generate on them. The aesteroids are filled with danger, but have more materials than you&amp;rsquo;d ever need to get through a shift.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 74 - (Meteor Swarm Revamp, Pipe Stacking Removal, General Game Balancing)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-06-16-liltenhead-74/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-06-16-liltenhead-74/</guid><description>The content freeze is over, and there were a number of notable PRs merged during the freeze and shortly after. Meteor swarms are now much more deadly and can breach through many layers of walls. Pipe stacking was removed, changing the way Atmos has to do pretty much everything. Many combat QoL additions were added, such as wielding autodropping items, shooting over stunned people, etc. Finally, there were a ton of QoL features and balance changes across various levels of content in the game.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 73 - (Ghost Role Raffles, Bullets Pass Over Crit Bodies, Robotics Console)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-12-liltenhead-73/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-12-liltenhead-73/</guid><description>This week brings loads of new features and content additions. Impactful ghost roles like ninjas or dragons now have a raffle before the role is given out. This gives all players interested in the role an equally random chance of obtaining the role once the timer ends. Space dragons can breathe fire now, ninjas have a new objective, and emagged cyborgs are more stealthy. Also this week, bullets will now pass over critically injured mobs unless you aim directly at them.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 72 - (Train Station, Sleeper Agents, Anti Rotting Chem)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-05-liltenhead-72/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-05-05-liltenhead-72/</guid><description>This week brings a new station to play on; it is named Train Station. The train station features departments stacked in a linear fashion that resembles a train shape. The syndicate not only sends agents at the beginning of a shift but may also awaken sleeper agents in the middle of the shift. Chemists can now make an anti-rot reagent with a little help from botany to prevent crew members from perma dying.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 71 - (New Map, Slime Species Update, Portable Recharger)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-28-liltenhead-71/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-28-liltenhead-71/</guid><description>This week brings a new station to play on; it is named Oasis. This station features a large park at its center and a massive mining-themed perma brig that is not attached to the station, which leaves a lot of room for unique gameplay. Syndicate librarians may now purchase cane swords; syndicates in general may now purchase syndicats. Science has received some tech tree changes, with the cargo telepad being bumped down to tier two, as well as new tier three tech under the arsenal tree provides a portable recharger for all your mobile battery needs.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 70 - (Loadouts, Jukebox, Killer Tomato)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-21-liltenhead-70/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-21-liltenhead-70/</guid><description>This week brings customizable role-specific loadouts. In the lobby, you can customize your loadout for every role, from jumpsuits to backpack types. Botanists can now grow their own personalized army through the form of killer tomatoes. The chameleon projector allows syndicate agents to blend into their environment by copying the appearance of nearly any object. As well as other content additions, bug fixes, and balancing tweaks over the week.</description></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 69 - (Botany QoL, Cryo Sleep Manifests)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-14-liltenhead-69/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-14-liltenhead-69/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 68 - (RCD Overhaul, New Anomaly Mechanics, Inventory QoL)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-10-liltenhead-68/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-04-10-liltenhead-68/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 67 - (Cleaning Grenades, Explosion Changes, Rubber Bullet Removal)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-31-liltenhead-67/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-31-liltenhead-67/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 66 - (Throwing Knives, Lone Ops Buff, Hacking Tweaks)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-24-liltenhead-66/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-24-liltenhead-66/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Update Vlog - 65 - Additions (IED Changes, Pipebomb, Plant Biomass Reclaimer)</title><link>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-18-liltenhead-65/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spacestation14.com/updates/24-03-18-liltenhead-65/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>